Dwayne Weller

Atlanta, GA 30127 | dpweller85@gmail.com

https://github.com/Dwaynew85 | https://www.dwayneweller.com

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Always learning, passionate Full Stack Developer. Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript Object Oriented programming educated at The Flatiron School. Four years' prior experience as an IT Field Technician. Experienced entrepreneur, team builder, relationship-focused leadership. Using my strong skills in problem solving, critical thinking, and solution seeking to drive continuous growth to better the lives of the people everywhere.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS, SQL, NoSQL, Bootstrap, Ruby, MVC, Application Programming Interface (API), TypeScript, CRUD, MongoDB, Express, JSON, JSX, XML, Redux, NPM, Git | Github, Rspec, Python, Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL), AWS, Google Cloud Platform (GCP)

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Dynamic Media Portal – Retail Media Platform - Website

An add platform to manage marketing campaigns for Home Depot brands on Facebook, Google, and Pinterest

- Implement React Context API to distribute API data and reduce component drilling
- Improve application style and interface using Ant design
- Apply ESLint to implement single standard of programming over various engineering teams

Fortnite Store ReactJS - Single Page Ecommerce Site - Github | Demo

An ecommerce site showcasing Fortnite products built with ReactJS frontend and a Ruby on Rails backend

- Employed react-router to manage RESTful routing between app pages
- Styled using vanilla CSS to customize design to improve user experience
- Built async actions and redux-thunk middleware to send data and receive data from server

EXPERIENCE

Home Depot Atlanta, GA Software Engineer 1/2022 - Present

- Leverage ReactJS, NodeJS, and Cypress to maintain and improve Home Depot's ad platform.
- Investigate JavaScript libraries, like global state management libraries, to improve data flow and reduce API calls.
- Utilize ReactJS to update platform UI, improving customer engagement by 13%.
- Update Jest integration test to improve code coverage of entire application by 37%.
- Reduce tech debt by 70% to improve application reliability and stability.
- Collaborate with an Agile team to coordinate project focuses and improves.

Accenture Atlanta, GA

Application Development Associate

10/2021 - 12/2021 Support the core of Accenture's Technology business using curiosity to solve Technology problems through

- developing, designing, and maintaining software products or systems that enable client strategies.
- Work with team members to design, implement, and test user/system requirements.
- Work across the Service Delivery Lifecycle on engineering solutions for new system roll-outs, major/minor enhancements, and /or ongoing maintenance of existing applications. To refactor JavaScript apps for readability and performance improvements.

AT&T Internet & Entertainment Field Service Wire Technician

Powder Springs, GA 10/2015 - 11/2019

- Engaged directly with customers, management, team members, and other technical support staff to assist and educate with various communication platforms, averaging a weekly caseload of 25 customers.
- Improved work order efficiency by increasing production 2x to 3x more customers served. Increased customer resolutions by an average 140%.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Online 03/2020 - 02/2021

Full Stack Web Development, Software Engineering Certification

Decatur, GA 01/2014 - 06/2014

DeVry University Computer Information Systems